Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/suhasmaddali (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership Public Speaking Typist

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Kannada (Professional Working)
French (Elementary)
Telugu (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Deploying Machine Learning Models in Production

Complete Python Bootcamp: Go From Zero To Hero

Machine Learning Modeling Pipelines in Production

Suhas Maddali

Northeastern University (MS in Data Science) | Ex-Data Scientist Intern @ NVIDIA | Arizona State University | Machine Learning Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Summary

My GitHub Portfolio: Github.com/suhasmaddali
I have 4+ years of experience in the field of data science and
machine learning. I've worked at NVIDIA, Solbots Technologies etc
as a data scientist and gave a lot of value by building ML models and
predictions.

I worked on a large number of projects with industries ranging from retail, manufacturing, automobile, agricultural and pharmaceutical industries.

I've created a GitHub portfolio that showcases my experience, skills and certifications in the field of data science and machine learning. In addition, detailed descriptions about the project are given to highlight various approaches at solving ML problems.

Throughout my experience, I worked with various algorithms in Supervised Learning: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Neural Networks, Support Vector Machines (SVMs), GBDT, XGBoost, Neural Networks and many others. In addition to this, I also worked with Unsupervised Learning: K -Means, PCA, Anomaly Detection, Association rules, and SVD.

Moreover, I am also a typing expert (99.9th percentile fastest typist in the world) with an average speed of 110 Words Per Minute (WPM). I have my best typing speed of 156 WPM.

Experience

Khoury College of Computer Sciences
Graduate Teaching Assistant - Supervised Machine Learning
August 2022 - December 2022 (5 months)
Boston, Massachusetts, United States

- Worked as a teaching assistant for the course "Supervised Machine Learning".
- Guided the students in the right direction and ensuring that they are organized to perform the best in class.
- Constantly updated my knowledge about machine learning and data science to suggest professors to make changes in the syllabus.

NVIDIA

Data Scientist

May 2022 - August 2022 (4 months)

Santa Clara, California, United States

- Worked on building the time series forecasting models to make predictions about the future supply based on the predictors or features from the data.
- Extracted helpful information and data from SAP systems to build interesting machine learning state-of-the-art models to generate forecasts both for the short term and the long term.
- Performed Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) and Visualization to find hidden trends and patterns in the data which could be used by the business to solve challenging problems in the supply chain.
- Focused on building explainable machine learning models so that the business stakeholders can understand ML predictions.

Northeastern University

Graduate Teaching Assistant - Natural Language Processing January 2022 - May 2022 (5 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

- Graduate Teaching Assistant (TA) for the course Natural Language
 Processing (CS 6120) under Uzair Ahmed.
- I'm given tasks such as teaching students natural language processing (NLP) concepts that require more clarification and understanding.
- I'm involved in grading the assignments, preparing them and also ensuring that students meet report the assignments on time.
- $^{\circ}$ I'm also involved in scheduling the office hours where the doubts are clarified for the students.

Khoury College of Computer Sciences Graduate Research Assistant - Neural Networks Verification December 2021 - April 2022 (5 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Research Assistant under professor Tan Cheng.

- Worked with Neural Network Verification and checked their specification.
- Implemented and programmed in Julia to check the working of the Deep Neural Networks.
- Verified the working of Neural networks in databases and systems.
- Defined the specifications of the Neural Networks to ensure that they meet the requirements as defined on the research papers.

Solbots Technologies Pvt LTD Data Scientist January 2018 - August 2020 (2 years 8 months) Hyderabad Area, India

- Contributed to the development of a bionic hand for amputees at Solbots Technologies Pvt LTD.
- Assisted in the design and manufacturing of the bionic hand, which helps amputees perform everyday tasks such as eating, drinking and operating a remote.
- Worked as a data scientist and wrote code to understand the type of object in front of the artificial hand using deep neural networks and advanced concepts of machine learning.
- Improved the accuracy of object prediction to ensure the hand can fully understand the object and not mistake it for another, thus maintaining a proper grip.
- Utilized speech recognition to activate or deactivate the hand using algorithms such as LSTM and GRUs.

Contributed to the team effort to provide amputees with a solution to live a better and fulfilling life.

Applied Al Course Applied Al Bootcamp April 2019 - August 2019 (5 months)

- Completed a 150+ hour course in data science and machine learning,
 gaining expertise in key concepts and real-world application through hands-on assignments and working with real data sets.
- Developed a strong understanding of data visualization, machine learning algorithms, and deep learning techniques.
- Had the opportunity to work on real-world data sets and problems, gaining valuable experience in applying data science and machine learning to solve business challenges.
- The course prepared me to tackle real-world business problems using data visualization, machine learning, and deep learning.

Education

Northeastern University

Master's degree, Data Science · (2021 - 2023)

Arizona State University

Masters, Computer Software Engineering · (September 2020 - May 2021)

VNR Vignanajyothi Institute of Engineering & Technology Electronics and communication engineering (2015 - 2019)